June
Shogi
Hall
（松本(まつもと)）ウオ〜ッ…　でかっ！
They're huge!
（三角(みすみ)）これ 誰の靴？
（松本）すっげえ！　でけえ！
Whose shoes are these?
They're freaking enormous!
（松本）うわ　隈倉(くまくら)九段のじゃね？
Kumakura, 9-dan's, right?
Most likely.
（三角）だよな
今日 棋竜戦の予選やってるもんな
He's here for the qualifier for
the Shogi Dragon Tournament.
ちょっと サイズいくつ？
見てみねえ？
Hey, what size is it?
Want to check?
Yeah, yeah!
Rumble
Whoa, 29.5 cm!
（松本）すげえ！　29,5センチ
まさかの約30センチ！
Rumble
Almost 30 cm!
（三角）さすが
旅館の壁を蹴り抜くだけあるぜ
That's how he kicked that hole in the inn's wall!
Rumble
These are beyond human!
ものが違う
もう絶対 ゲタ箱入んねえ
You can't fit them into a cubbyhole!
But I was shocked, you know?
でも びっくりしたよな
Hard to imagine the cool, stone-faced Kumakura
kicking the wall of an inn after losing a title match...
あの いつも岩のように
冷静な隈倉さんが—
タイトル戦で負けて
旅館の壁を蹴り抜くなんて
I never realized he had so much hidden passion beneath that calm exterior.
あの静けさの裏に
そんな熱さを隠していたなんて…
ク〜ッ！　ますます かっけえ！
That makes him so much more cooler!
ンンッ…　俺も蹴り抜きてえ！
I'm gonna start kicking too!
ウワッ！
Kengo, you the man!
健吾(けんご) イカす〜！
I bet if I put these on, I can get better!
これ履いたら
俺 強くなれんじゃね？
I'll get closer to Class A!
Ａ級に近づけんじゃね？　ンンッ…
I'm starting to believe that!
…とまで思えてきた！
You might be right!
なれるかもよ！
（指を鳴らす音）
近づけんじゃね？
You could get closer!
What do you think?
（松本）どうよ？　どうよ スミス
なれそう？　Ａ級
What do you think, Smith? You think I can be Class A?
His feet are huge!
（三角）
足でかっ！　バランスわるっ！
You're really unbalanced.
But that's fine!
でも いい！
（隈倉）うん？
盛り上がってるところ すまんが
Sorry to interrupt when you're having a good time,
but can I have my shoes back?
靴 いいかな？
S-Sorry!
（三角）サ… サーセン！
（松本）すんません　押忍(おす)！
I-I'm sorry!
（松本）キャ〜！
（三角）ハワ〜！
はぁ…　でけえ　かっけえ
Such a giant. So cool.
Look at that trunk.
（三角）見ろよ あの体幹
もはや棋士の体じゃねえよ
That's not a professional shogi player's body.
Is it true he's a 5-dan in judo?
柔道五段ってホント？
I heard he was invited to join a
mixed martial arts organization!
（松本）あっ 俺 格闘技団体から
誘い来たって聞いたぜ
Crap! It's already been 25 minutes?
（三角）
あっ いけねえ　もう25分？
Our precious 50-minute lunch break will be over soon!
50分しかねえ大事な昼食休憩が
終わってしまう！
Hurry!
（松本）急げ　しまった！
Oh no! We've only got time for the soba shop on the corner!
これだと 角の六角(ろっかく)そばしか
間に合わないや！
Shogi
Hall
The clouds adorning the setting sun whispered "It's gonna be your turn next" into my ear
But now that they've grown tired of just killing time I'm sure I'll just be their scapegoat
But I'm the king of my very own world
I can even run on top of water
I'm the egg who can put itself back together again after a fall
And can even go on to become an astronaut
I'm sure if I pick up all the beads that rained from the sky and gather them up
Then one day I'll finally be able to plant a flag which signifies my very own liberty
So I pull on my ripped jeans and fight back the tears the draft brings
I exhale a big gulp of air and then another 'cause I'm a boxer rising up again
You only get one chance to come back from the brink
So pound on that door you painted yourself
The colorful ink disperses into two paths
But you're the one who decides how your flower blooms
（二海堂(にかいどう)）ふ〜む…
Nikaidou Family Special
30-item Bland, Healthy Square Partitioned Lunch Box
So we've both cleared our first match, huh?
まずは お互い
初戦はクリアか
The Rookie Tournament is for
players 26-years-old and younger.
（二海堂）新人戦は26歳以下
Plump
Moist
Luxurious
Chew, chew.
Players 5-dan and below can compete.
五段以下の棋士で争われる…
Chew, chew.
There are 42 players in the tournament.
総勢42名の棋戦！
Chew, chew.
However...
…なわけだが！
Nom, nom.
マグモグ…
You're always eating healthy but fancy food.
（零(れい)）いつ見ても
ヘルシー アンド 豪華だよな
You should either eat or talk.
食べるか しゃべるか
どっちかにしろよ
（二海堂）いいか？
Listen.
If we win three more times, we'll reach the finals.
あと３回勝ったら
決勝だ
You and I won't face off at any
class-promotion tournaments this year.
お前と俺は
順位戦で 今年は対局がない
Finals
Wipe
*The Legend Begins!
Finals
You need to hang in there, no matter what,
so we can battle each other in an official match!
公式戦で戦うためには お前には
なんとしても残ってもらわねば！
*The Legend Begins!
Finals
"I need to hang in there"?
“お前には”って…
It sounds like you're pretty confident about getting to the finals.
自分は もう既に
残る気満々なセリフだな
Where does that confidence come from?
どっから来るんだ？　その自信
ンンッ！　いいか？
なんとしてでも決勝に残れ！
Listen!
Whatever you do, make it to the finals!
That's where our legend begins!
俺と お前の
伝説の始まりなんだぞ！
Project X!
~The Rivals Are Best Friends~
Master Nikaidou's Challenge
After I become a Master,
（二海堂）
俺が 見事 名人になって—
I'll get featured on a program like Project X,
「プロジェクトＸ」的な番組で
特集されたとき—
and they'll show black-and-white
stills of that match!
モノクロ静止画像で
差し込まれるんだよ そのもようが
That's what Nikaidou thought at the time.
（ナレーション）
そのとき 二海堂は …思った
Quiver
Heartrending
It'll have narration like that!
Quiver
…みたいなナレーションと一緒にな
Hey, you're getting way too deep into that future outlook of yours.
おい お前　鮮明に
作り込み過ぎだぞ　その未来予想図
Quiver
Also, are you crying?
…つか もう泣いてる？
（有本(ありもと)）
新人戦か　何もかも皆 懐かしい
The Rookie Tournament, huh?
That brings back a lot of memories.
Gasp
But kid, you should only indulge in such idle chatter after you beat this old man today.
だが 坊主　そんな与太話は
今日 このじじいに勝ってからだぞ
こら
Got that?
Smile
A pie in the sky is tasty, but it won't fill you up.
絵に描いた餅は うまいが
腹にたまらんぞ　ハハハハッ…
Smile
Right! I'm looking forward to our match today.
はい！　今日は
どうぞ よろしくお願いいたします
お食事中 騒いで すみません！
I'm sorry we interrupted your lunch!
What's your problem, Kiriyama?!
（二海堂）どうしてくれる 桐山(きりやま)！
お前のせいで怒られたろう！
He got mad at us because of you!
The gentle Arimoto, 9-dan, got mad!
Gwarrr
あの温厚な有本九段に！
うぎーっ！
No matter how you look at it, it's all your fault.
どこを どう見ても
全て お前のせいだよ
Talking loudly about winning a title,
becoming a Master, and going on NHK's Top Runner...
大声で 賞を取りたいだの—
名人になって ＮＨＫの
「トップランナー」に出たいだの…
Kiriyama,
（二海堂）桐山
you're always doing that "Oh, I'm not greedy" air, like you're watching with the cool detachment of a spectator,
お前は いっつも そうやって—
“僕は がっついてません”的な
風情で—
涼しげに高みの見物的な
ポジションぶってるが—
but I know what's up.
俺には分かっているんだぞ
What?
About this Rookie King title, you're like,
お前 新人王は—
"Well, if I play properly, I can win it without much hassle."
“まあ 順当にいけば
普通に取れるだろうし”
Am I right?
…とか思ってるだろう？
Excuse me?
は･い？
Wh-Where is that coming from?
い… いきなり何ですか？
はい？
What?
"I don't need to make a fuss about the
Rookie King title because of course I'll win it.
（二海堂）
“新人王は大騒ぎしなくても
まあ 取れて当たり前”
“むしろ 年齢制限的には
まだ全然 余裕だけど—”
In fact,
regarding the age restriction, I'm totally confident,
but if I had to worry about anything, I think I'm getting closer to 6-dan,
“まあ 不安要素っていえば—”
“俺 多分 近々 昇級して
六段になっちゃうから—”
so if I don't win soon, I may miss my chance.
“早く取らないと
取りっぱぐれちゃうかもだな”
Well, I'll cross that bridge when I come to it.
“まあ
そんときゃ そんときで—”
There are plenty of other title matches, so I could always work hard for those."
“ほかにもタイトル戦は
たくさんあるから—”
“そこで頑張ればいっか”
…くらいに思ってるだろう？
That's more or less what you're
thinking deep in your heart, isn't it?!
心の中ではな！
Huh?
はぁ？　なに？　それ
思ってるわけねえだろう
What are you talking about? Of course I don't think that.
Where do you come up with these ridiculous ideas?
何をそんなバカげたこと…
…たく
Sheesh.
ンンッ…
そんなこと あるわけ… あるわけ…
I would never...
I would...
Huh?
えっ？　あれ？
Wait.
Blush
Kiriyama didn't realize it?
（棋士Ａ）
気づいてなかったのか 桐山よ
That brat pisses me off.
頭来るな このガキ　…たく
かわいいな　こんちくしょう！
Jeez.
That's adorable, though, dammit!
That's what I can't stand about a junior high prodigy going pro.
（棋士Ｂ）あ〜あ…　これだから
中学生デビューの神童さんは
Ticks me off.
…たく 腹立つわ
このおバカさんめ！
That idiot!
Look at him blushing, the ninny.
（棋士Ｃ）
真っ赤になっとる　アホか
God help me, that's cute.
くそかわいいじゃねえか
Relax, Kiriyama!
安心しろ 桐山
No matter how puffed up you get with success
and pretend to be a fake herbivore shogi player,
お前が どんな おごり高ぶった
偽りの草食棋士だとしても—
I won't abandon you over something like that!
そんなことくらいで
俺は お前を見捨てたりしない！
That's because...
なぜなら
俺こそが唯一のお前の理解者…
I'm the only one who understands you.
(Rivals)
Because we're best friends!
心友(しんゆう)だからな！
(Rivals)
ウワ〜ッ！　恥ずかしい！
俺 最低！　ウワッ…
This is so embarrassing!
Dash
I'm the worst!
Hey, wait! We're not done talking!
（二海堂）…て おい 待てよ！
話は まだ終わってねえよ！
（零）アア〜ッ…
（有本）あ〜あ…
Oh man.
He's so shaken.
動揺しとる　フフッ…
ガラスの10代だのぅ
A fragile teenager.
Just leave him be, Nikaidou. It's funnier this way.
まあ 放っとけ 二海堂　面白いから
Kiriyama.
桐山…
Good grief, Kiriyama.
…たく 桐山　気にせんでも
もとより ここは鬼の住みか
You don't have to worry,
since this was always a den for demons.
You'll only find the strong-willed here,
all as arrogant as a fiery soul.
火の玉みたいに傲慢で
気の強い人間しか おらんのにな
Word of mouth is steadily driving up sales of our Puffy-Puffy Snowman.
（相米二(そめじ)）
え〜 “ふくふくダルマ”は—
口コミで
徐々に売り上げを伸ばし—
They're really starting to take
root as a March City specialty.
三月町(さんがつちょう)名物として
見事 根づき始めた
And it's all thanks to you girls.
これも お前たちのおかげだ
じいちゃん うれしいぞ
You've made Grandpa really happy.
Bam!
And so, would you help me think of an idea for a new sweet?
（相米二）
…というわけで 何か新しい菓子を
また一緒に考えてくんねえか？
（あかり）
う〜ん…　今度は夏の和菓子か
This one will be a summer confection, huh?
Something that looks refreshing
見た目は涼しげで
冷たい緑茶に合うような…
and would go well with cold, green tea...
Purr, purr...
（クロちゃん）ゴロゴロ
かつお節か煮干しをね—
Have any dried bonito or dried sardines?
ほんのちょっとでいいんですよ
I'd be satisfied with just a little.
Can you please pet me a little?
（ミケちゃん）
ちょっと ひとなでなど
してくださりませんか？
But when it comes to summer,
our go-to is the waterfront series that uses agar, right?
（あかり）でも 夏といったら
やっぱり 寒天を使った—
水辺シリーズが定番よね
That's right. It's important to stick to the basics.
（相米二）
そうなんだよ　定番は大事だ
そこに ちょい〜と
目新しさが加われば言うことねえ
It would be perfect if we could add just a little novelty to that.
Scribble
Momo, any ideas?
（相米二）モモ　何かねえか？
（モモ）うん？
Scribble
Like, what would be fun to see floating in the pond?
こう… お池にな
何が浮いてたら楽しい？
What do you like?
何が好きだ？
Let's see...
（モモ）う〜んとね…
（モモ）アヒルさん！
A duck?
Ducks, huh?
（相米二）アヒルか！
あ〜 いいな！　かわいいぞ！
Nice! That'd be cute!
That's my granddaughter!
さすが 我が孫！
Oh, but if customers bought it as a souvenir,
the duck could fall off while they're walking with it.
あっ でも お土産にしたとき
持ち歩いているうちに—
アヒルが落ちちゃわないかしら？
Good point.
（相米二）あっ そうか
As a gift, that shouldn't happen.
贈り物で それは
絶対あってはいかんことだな
う〜ん…　じゃ 沈めてみたら
どうだ？　寒天の中に
What if we sunk it?
Inside the block of agar?
ンンッ…　なんか—
All of a sudden, it's become something else.
急に いまひとつになったな
Something... kind of sinister?
こう… 不吉っていうか
モモ　ほかにも何かねえか？
Momo, any other ideas?
Like something that splashes into the water.
こう… ポチャ〜ンと—
Scribble
水の中に入ってるやつだ
何か思いつかねえか？
Scribble
Does that bring anything to mind?
Splashes...
水の中…
into the water?
ポチャ〜ン…
A sandal?
サンダル！
アア〜ッ！
モモのサンダル 落っこった！
I dropped my sandal!
（あかり）あ〜あ…　泣かないの
また買ってあげるから
Don't cry.
I'll buy you new ones.
(*A visualization)
（モモの泣き声）
落っことしちゃったね
It dropped in there, huh?
It's okay, it's okay.
A sandal, she says?
サンダル …だと!?
We've got a child prodigy here!
（相米二）神童キタコレー！
Could this girl be a blessing from the god of sweets?
もしや この子は
和菓子の神の祝福を？
My granddaughter is the best!
わしの孫 最高！
新しすぎる その感性　アハハッ…
That sensibility is fresh and then some!
It'll be a hit!
売れる〜っ！
What?
（モモの はしゃぎ声）
（あかり）え〜っ？　おじいちゃん
Grandpa...
Will Crescent Moon be okay?
三日月堂(みかづきどう) 大丈夫かな？
ホント おじいちゃんには困ったな
ねえ？　ひな
Honestly, what are we going to do with you, Grandpa?
Right, Hina?
Hina!
（あかり）
ひな　お待たせ　お風呂 空いたよ
Sorry for the wait.
The bath's open.
What's wrong?
どうしたの？　元気ないね
You seem down.
Oh, no.
（ひなた）
ううん　そんなことないよ
I'm fine.
Well then...
（ひなた）さてと…
I'll go take a bath.
ひなも お風呂入ろうっと
In that case, don't forget the fire.
（あかり）じゃ 火の元 お願いね
You're the last one, so be sure to put it out.
ひな 最後だから ちゃんと止めてね
Got it.
（ひなた）うん 分かった
Goodnight.
（あかり）おやすみ
（ひなた）おやすみなさい
Come to think of it,
そういえば
今日は ご飯も ちょっと残してた
she left some food on her plate tonight.
Hina...
ひな 学校で何かあったのかな
I wonder if something happened at school.
June
Ladybug Bush (Part 1)
Egg Salad Sandwich
Thank you!
Fujimori Bakery
（店員）ありがとうございました
おお　ホントだ　おいしい
Wow, it's true.
It's really good.
Bought some
for lunch too
The egg salad sandwich from Fujimori Bakery on 2nd Street is delicious!
（あかり）２丁目の
フジモリパンのタマゴサンド
すっごく おいしいのよ
Love
Kiss
They're open pretty early, so if you have a match,
you could buy your breakfast there and eat it on the way.
朝早くから
やってるから—
Love
Kiss
対局の日とか買って
食べながら行くといいよ
Love
Kiss
（ミケちゃん）
ニャー　おねえさん 好き
I love you, Sis!
Fujimori Bakery?
フジモリパン!?
Rei, the donuts there are great!
零ちゃん あすこはね
ドーナツが おいしいの！
食べて！　絶対 食べて！
Try them.
You have to try them!
If you go there in the evening,
you'll get them freshly deep fried.
夕方に行くと
揚げたてが買えるから
Maybe I should've gotten donuts like Hina recommended too.
（零）ドーナツも買えばよかったな
ひなちゃんオススメの
Then I could've had them as a snack during the match.
そしたら
対局中のおやつにできたのに
In today's open tournament,
the amount of time each player has is short.
（零）
今日のオープントーナメントは
持ち時間の短い対局だ
It starts at 10 o'clock, so I can go in 15 minutes before that.
10時からだから
15分前には入るとして…
I still have time, so I'll eat out here.
まだ大丈夫だな
ここで食べてっちゃおう
対局相手は
何度か当たったことがある—
I've played against my opponent today a number of times before.
He's good at playing quick matches.
早指しに強い相手だ
Maybe he'll go with the Fujii System...
多分 藤井(ふじい)システム
In that case, it'll be a fast match.
だとしたら 急戦で…
この木…
That bush...
That's right. I remember.
そうだ　覚えてる
小学校の校庭に植えてあった
There was one in the yard of my elementary school.
てんとう虫の木だ
A ladybug bush.
Out of all the bushes there,
たくさんあった植木の中で—
for some reason, ladybugs only laid their eggs on that bush.
なぜか この木にしか
てんとう虫は卵を産まなかった
I haven't seen one in a long time.
久しぶりに見た　懐かしいな
It makes me feel nostalgic.
“懐かしい”？
Nostalgic?
No, that's not right.
いや 違う
This is...
これは… この気持ちは…
This feeling is...
Uh-oh! He's looking at us!
（男の子Ａ）
やべえよ　こっち見てるよ
（男の子Ｂ）怖(こえ)え！
（男の子Ｃ）メガネロボット！
I'm scared!
Four-eyed robot!
（男の子Ｄ）投げたのお前だろう？
You're the one who threw it!
After I lost my parents and little sister to a car accident,
（零）両親と妹が
事故で消えてしまって—
I became the child of a shogi family in Tokyo.
僕は 東京の将棋の家の子になった
My school in Nagano was small, and I was all alone.
長野では小さな学校で
独りぼっちだったけど—
But after coming to Tokyo,
東京に来たら
大きな大きな学校の中で—
I learned the true meaning of being all alone in my huge new school.
本物の独りぼっちになってしまった
Still, I'd never had a single friend before,
でも 友達なんて
１回も持ったことがなかったから…
Kiriyama
Four-eyes
Shogi
Robot
Take off!
so that was normal for me.
僕には それが普通だった
“普通だ”…
"It's normal."
That's what I tried to think.
…と思おうとした
Shogi
Hall
I went as far as to make myself unnoticeable so the direct attacks on me from my classmates wouldn't escalate.
クラスメートたちの
直接攻撃を悪化させないために—
僕は ひたすら気配を消した
I was used to that kind of thing,
そういうのには慣れていたから
毎日 淡々と行動した
so I acted indifferent about it every day.
During recess, I would pretend to be absorbed in a book.
休み時間は
本に夢中になってるフリをして—
And for lunch break, I'd stand out if I stayed in the room,
お昼休みは
教室に残っていると目立つから…
so I'd hide in the bushes in a corner of the schoolyard.
校庭の隅の植木の中に隠れてた
Pass me the ball!
（男の子Ａ）ボール こっち！
（男の子Ｃ）ハハハハッ…
R-2c+.
（零）２三飛成
Checkmate
Within
5 Moves
Checkmate
Within
5 Moves
Time
Trial
Kx2c.
同玉…
B-1c+.
１三角成
K-3d.
３四玉
My adoptive mother was kind.
（零）
幸田(こうだ)のお義母(かあ)さんは優しい人で
Good morning.
（零）おはようございます
（棋士Ｄ）おう おはよう
Morning.
She always smiled with a worried expression.
（零）いつも
困ったような顔で笑っていた
I did everything I could think of to please her, but...
僕は お義母さんに喜んでほしくて
いろいろ頑張ったけど…
（香子(きょうこ)）米とぎ？
Wash the rice?
Why don't you have Rei do it?
零にやらせればいいじゃない
うまいんでしょう？　私より
He's better at it than I am, isn't he?
（ゲーム音声）
（歩(あゆむ)）風呂掃除？
Clean the bathtub?
You should make Rei do it.
零にやってもらえばいいじゃん
You're always saying that he's such a good boy, Mom.
母さん いっつも
“いい子”だって言ってんじゃん
The more I helped around the house...
（零）僕が手伝えば手伝うほど…
the more troubled she looked.
お義母さんは ますます困った顔に
なっていってしまった
Let's have a good match.
（零･棋士Ｅ）
よろしくお願いします
Listen, could you quit trying to be so obvious about scoring points?
（歩）あのさ
そうやって分かりやすく—
ポイント稼ぎすんの
やめてくんないかな
She's our mom.
僕たちのお母さんなんだけど
I hate him.
嫌いよ　だって気味悪い
ロボットみたいなんだもの
He's so creepy.
He's like a robot.
When night came,
（零）夜になると—
I would get stressed out,
wondering if the rest of my life would be like this.
自分は これから ずっと
このままなのかと不安になって—
I couldn't even breathe.
息もできなかった
And so I tried to become completely absorbed in shogi.
（零）だから
何も考えなくて済むように—
Then I wouldn't have to think about anything else.
のめり込むように盤に向かった
For the longest time,
ずっと 足のつかない夜の海に—
my days were like bobbing on a sea at night,
with my legs failing to reach the bottom.
浮かんでいるような日々だった
All I had that I could cling to...
この小さな盤しか すがれるものは
もはや なかった
was this little board.
I would solve every last one of the shogi checkmate problems
詰め将棋は出ている書籍を
片っ端から解きまくり—
and read until I broke out into a fever.
熱が出るほど読み込んだ
Then I moved on to the untouched shogi match records in Dad's study—50 years' worth of official matches.
そして 父の書庫に眠っていた—
全公式戦の棋譜 50余年分
In there, beautifully preserved shogi match records from the Edo period were stored.
そこから 美しく閉じられた
江戸(えど)時代の棋譜まで—
I would study them day and night.
昼も夜もなく並べ続け
I'd spend all of my days off at the shogi hall,
休みは全て将棋会館や…
父の紹介の将棋道場で
朝から晩まで対局をした
or playing from morning to night at a
shogi training hall Dad introduced me to.
I would play,
指して 指して 指して 指して
and play,
指し続けて…
and keep playing...
（棋士Ｅ）負けました
I lost.
I would play,
（零）指して 指して
and play,
指して 指して 指して 指して
and play...
Kawamoto Akari
Dinner
Come over for dinner tonight. We're having Salisbury steak.
Akari
Kawamoto Akari
Dinner
Come over for dinner tonight. We're having Salisbury steak.
Akari
Kawamoto Akari
Dinner
Come over for dinner tonight. We're having Salisbury steak.
Akari
Kawamoto Akari
Dinner
Come over for dinner tonight. We're having Salisbury steak.
Akari
Kawamoto Akari
Dinner
Come over for dinner tonight. We're having Salisbury steak.
Akari
Kawamoto Akari
Dinner
Come over for dinner tonight. We're having Salisbury steak.
Akari
Kawamoto Akari
Dinner
Come over for dinner tonight. We're having Salisbury steak.
Akari
そうして僕は 今ここにいる
And so, that's how I'm here right now.
I wonder why I'm smiling
The night wears on as I trace it with a finger
In the oversized nooks of this world
My heart continues to melt away
Like the petals of a flower repelling the rain yet refusing to wither
All the things important to me have spilled out
Before I knew it I was all alone and I'd walked a great distance
I'd forgotten what my own voice really sounded like
And it was the strangest feeling
After dawn broke on that long night
I remembered as if it were all a dream
I gave myself up to that nostalgic eternity
And it seems like I can go on walking again
Welcome.
（あかり）
いらっしゃい　まあ ドーナツ！
Oh, donuts!
You bought them for us?
（あかり）買ってきてくれたの？
Fujimori Bakery
They're still a little warm.
まだ ちょっぴり温(あった)かいわ
揚げたてね
Freshly deep fried, huh?
Gleam
I wanna eat donuts!
ドーナツ 食べたい！
うん
もう温かいうちに食べちゃいたいな
It would be nice to eat them while they're still warm.
But then we wouldn't have room for dinner.
でも 食べたら
晩ご飯 入んなくなっちゃうし
あっ ひなは
まだ帰ってきてないのよ　遅いわね
Hina isn't home yet.
She's late.
（モモたち）ニャ！
What?! Can I partake?!
（ミケちゃん）何スか？
いただいていいんスか？
Is it okay?! Can I have some?!
（シロちゃん）
いいんスか？　食べていいんスか？
（鳴き声）
（零）手が ながっ！
Such long arms!
（あかり）
あっ ひな ちょうど帰ってきたわね
There she is now.
Welcome home!
おかえりなさ〜い
I wonder what's wrong.
どうしたのかしら
ひな？　ひなでしょう？
Hina?
That's you, right?
（あかり）ひな？
Rei...
零ちゃん…　お… お姉ちゃん
S-Sis...
Hina!
（零）ひなちゃん！
Ladybug Bush (Part 1)
Next Episode Preview
Episode 26
Rei brought over several
books of beautiful sweets.
（ひなた）零ちゃんが
持ってきてくれたのは
とても美しい
和菓子の本たちだった
I see.
（零）そうか
What I've always called
a two-starred ladybug
〝二つ星テントウ〞って
ずっと呼んでた これは
is actually called a Asian ladybeetle.
〝ナミテントウ〞って
名だったんだ
The Japanese name for ladybug means "insect on the path to Heaven"?
（ひなた）
てんとう虫って
〝天道虫(てんどうむし)〞って書くの？
I wonder why.
なんでかな？
Illustration: Yonezu Kenshi
Go ahead, Momo!
（相米二）ほれ モモ
言ってやれ！
（モモ）
「３月のライオン」
また見てね
Please watch "March comes in like a lion" again!
（相米二）モモは世界一
いや 宇宙一の孫じゃ！
Momo is the world's—
no, the galaxy's best granddaughter!